<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>myarik</title>
    <link>http://myarik.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on myarik</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2019 17:15:11 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://myarik.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://myarik.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2019 17:15:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://myarik.com/about/</guid>
      <description>I am Yaroslav Muravskyi. Technology is a passion of mine, and I enjoy learning new things and challenging myself. I love building products that solve real, human problems.
Work I Technical Leader &amp;amp; Software engineer. The things, I like about my job is:
 Work on designing functional technology solutions Work on processes in my team Growing as a technical leader &amp;amp; engineer  Stack I work with python, golang, and javascript.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The effective use of Django ORM</title>
      <link>http://myarik.com/talks/django_orm_tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 19:44:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://myarik.com/talks/django_orm_tips/</guid>
      <description>This talk describes how to use Django ORM effectively. Main topics: - Django ORM Mistakes
- Performance Problems in the Django ORM - Database concurrency in Django the right way
 Slides: SlideShare</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Поиск в Django REST Framework с помощью Elasticsearch</title>
      <link>http://myarik.com/posts/poisk-v-django-rest-framework-s-pomoschyu-elasticsearch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 19:51:43 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://myarik.com/posts/poisk-v-django-rest-framework-s-pomoschyu-elasticsearch/</guid>
      <description>Пользователи ищут товары в интернет-магазине, ищут стати, поиск это неотъемлемый компонент сайта. Быстрый и гибкий поиск сложно реализовать средствами реляционных баз данных. Для таких задач используют поисковые движки, один из которых Elasticsearch. Elasticsearch хорошо документирован и доступен из коробки на AWS.
Для работы с elasticsearch используется библиотека elasticsearch-py или elasticsearch-dsl-py. elasticsearch-dsl-py это надстройка над elasticsearch-py, она проста в использовании и поддерживает elasticsearch версии 5.x. На базе этой библиотеки была создана библиотеку django-rest-elasticsearch, которая основана на идеологии существующего поиска в Django REST Framework.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to integrate Django REST Framework and Elasticsearch</title>
      <link>http://myarik.com/talks/drf_and_elasticsearch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2017 19:29:50 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://myarik.com/talks/drf_and_elasticsearch/</guid>
      <description>This talk describes how to use the library django-rest-elasticsearch for integrating Elasticsearch with Django.
Slides: SlideShare</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>